R ABARNA

18, KAMARAJAPURAM 1ST STREET, THIRUMANGALAM - 625007

Phone: 97914-29891

Email:abarnarajkumar@yahoo.com

Skills

- Negotiating skills
- Communication Skills
- Problem solving skills
- Familiar with working of Ms Office
- Target oriented

Professional Summary

Experienced HR Trainer has excellent presentation and training abilities and understanding of how to identify corporate training needs. Excels at training program design and development of associated training materials. Has a Bachelor's Degree in English and Professional Degree in Human Resources Management and having six years of work experience.

Employment history

HR & Administrative Officer, Vishaal Promoters Pvt Ltd. Madurai Jan. 2019 – Aug 2019

- Communicate with customers, employees, and other individuals to answer questions, disseminate or explain information, take orders, and address complaints.
- Complete and mail bills, contracts, policies, invoices, or checks.
- Open, sort, and route incoming mail, answer correspondence, and prepare outgoing mail.
- Compile, copy, sort, and file records of office activities, business transactions, and other activities.
- Compute, record, and proofread data and other information, such as records or reports.
- Complete work schedules, manage calendars, and arrange appointments.
- Train other staff members to perform work activities, such as using computer applications.
- Prepare meeting agendas, attend meetings, and record and transcribe minutes.
- Supervise the work of office, administrative, or customer service employees to ensure adherence to quality standards, deadlines, and proper procedures, correcting errors or problems.
- Evaluate employees' job performance and conformance to regulations and recommend appropriate personnel action.
- Recruit, interview, and select employees.
- Interpret and communicate work procedures and company policies to staff.
- Prepare and issue work schedules, deadlines, and duty assignments for office or administrative staff.
- Maintain records pertaining to inventory, personnel, orders, supplies, or machine maintenance.
- Coordinate activities with other supervisory personnel or with other work units or departments.

Softskill Trainer & Placement Coordinator, Bharath Niketan Engineering College. Theni

Jul. 2011 – Aug. 2012

- Initiate, facilitate, and moderate classroom discussions.
- Prepare course materials such as syllabus, assignments and handouts.
- Evaluate and grade students' based on training performance.
- Advise students on academic and vocational curricular and career issues.
- Participate in student recruitment, registration, and placement activities.
- Participate in campus and community events.

English & Softskill Trainer, Vaelai Training and Research. Madurai

Jul. 2010 - Jul. 2011

- Adapt teaching methods and instructional materials to meet students' varying needs, abilities, and interests.
- Observe and evaluate students' work to determine progress and make suggestions for improvement.
- Conduct classes, workshops, and demonstrations to teach principles, techniques, or methods in subjects such as basic English language skills, life skills, and workforce entry skills.
- Instruct students individually and in groups, using various teaching methods such as lectures, discussions, and demonstrations.
- Prepare students for further education by encouraging them to explore learning opportunities and to persevere with challenging tasks.
- Plan and conduct activities for a balanced program of instruction, demonstration, and work time that provides students with opportunities to observe, question, and investigate.
- Prepare reports on students and activities as required by administration.

Process Executive, Cognizant BPO Services. Chennai

May. 2008 – Aug. 2009

- Procuring goods and Issue receipts, refunds, and credits due to customers.
- Assist customers by providing information and resolving their complaints.
- Answer customers' questions, and provide information on procedures or policies.
- Attending voice calls and clarify their queries

Education

Fatima College of Arts & Science, Madurai, TAMILNADU

MBA, HR, Apr. 2014

Fatima College of Arts & Science, Madurai, TAMILNADU

Bachelor of Arts, English, Apr. 2008